

Alexander Kuznetsov SOFTWARE ENGINEER JAVASCRIPT / REACT / NODE

PROFILE

3+ years professional experience JavaScript developer with industry experience building websites and web applications in different areas such as fintech, ecommerce, healthcare, telecom, and others.

Process automation enthusiast. 10+ years experience in IT area. CONTACTS

- alexandr.kuznecov@gmail.com
- https://github.com/AlexSKuznetsov
- in linkedin.com/in/AlexSKuznetsov
- ∅ @AlexSKuznetsov
- (L) +66 0648208814

SKILLS

Project Management

- Agile / Scrum, SDLC
- Jira / Confluence

Frontend

- React.js (w hooks) / Next.js / GraphQL
- TypeScript
- Redux / Redux Toolkit, React Query
- Headless CMS (JAMStack)
- Tailwind CSS, CSS in JS libs

Backend

- Node.js, Express.js
- Docker / Docker-compose
- PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Prisma ORM / Mongoose ORM

Cloud

AWS: IAM, EC2, Lambda, ELB, ASG, S3. CloudFront

Tools

- Git / GitHub / GitLab
- CI/CD
- · React Testing Library / Jest
- Webpack
- Figma

LANGUAGES

- Russian native
- English professional (B1+)

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EPAM SYSTEMS - IT company

March 2021 - Present

- US-based Healthcare project. Built patient education platform Web App with video content (Video.js, React, Context, Emotion, Storybook);
- EU-based Retail project. Developed the front-end part of pages and features for several eCommerce solutions (Next.js, Storybook, Styled-Components);

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

MTS Group - Telecom company

Sep 2020 - Mar 2021

- Developed B2B-order management platform with micro frontend approach (React, TypeScript, Web-components, Shadow DOM, Camunda Engine);
- Moved from an Excel-based order system to a modern platform that allows controlling all requests and orders.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

FinMedia - FinTech & AdTech integrator Sep 2019 - Apr 2020

- Built a high-performance communication system for the lead generation platform to control all communication channels to send financial offers to clients who have filled out a loan application;
- Design BPMN diagram to control communication process with Microservices approach (Camunda Engine);
- Audit previous communication process to determine gaps;
- Developed microservices for each of the communication services such as Email, SMS, Push, etc. (Node.js, Express.js, Docker)

BUSINESS ANALYST / BPM DEVELOPER

Locko Bank - Bankina

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

- Developed business process components for the automation loan process for retail customers on top of the BPM software (C#, Javascript);
- Automated the process of providing trade acquiring equipment for the small business customers;

EDUCATION HISTORY

Fullstack Javascript Developer

Mar 2020 - Jul 2020

Elbrus Coding Bootcamp

• 12-weeks intensive software development bootcamp learning various technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Redux, Redux-Thunk & Redux-Saga, Node, MongoDB, Express.js, Git.

Master's Degree, Risk management and investment analysis

2014 - 2015

Higher School of Economics

Bachelor's degree, Management and Marketing

2002 - 2008

Moscow Financial University under the Government of the Russian Federation